<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>TIL on Ben Sycha</title><link>https://ben.sycha.uk/til/</link><description>Recent content in TIL on Ben Sycha</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ben.sycha.uk/til/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GitHub pages custom url configuration</title><link>https://ben.sycha.uk/til/github-pages-custom-url/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ben.sycha.uk/til/github-pages-custom-url/</guid><description>Problem My &amp;lsquo;GitHub Pages&amp;rsquo; website keeps losing its custom url every time I push a new version! 🙄
Background I had originally used git hub actions to deploy my site based off of foosel&amp;rsquo;s work. Then I thought:
Hey, I have a local gitlab instance that I just set up a CI runner on&amp;hellip; so lets see if I can use that pipeline and have it push a fully build website to GitHub!</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="problem">Problem</h2>
<p>My &lsquo;GitHub Pages&rsquo; website keeps losing its custom url every time I push a new version! 🙄</p>
<h2 id="background">Background</h2>
<p>I had originally used git hub actions to deploy my site based off of <a href="https://github.com/foosel/foosel.github.io">foosel&rsquo;s</a> work. Then I thought:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Hey, I have a local gitlab instance that I just set up a CI runner on&hellip; so lets see if I can use that pipeline and have it push a fully build website to GitHub!</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>I then found when the website was updating it was losing its CNAME setting in GitHub pages settings web ui. I thought I can keep an eye on that and fix it when needed.</p>
<p>Then I noticed a grammatical mistake and quickly updated it while I was settling the kids down and got distracted so forgot to check and fix it&hellip;</p>
<h2 id="cause">Cause</h2>
<p>Turns out that when you configure a customdomain in GitHub pages using <em>Deploy from a branch</em> it actually adds a CNAME file to the root of your repository with the domain name in it. Of course I hadn&rsquo;t included this file in my build pipeline so every deployment the web UI created CNAME file was 💥<em><strong>OBLITERATED</strong></em>💥</p>
<h2 id="fix">Fix</h2>
<p>Simple, add create a CNAME file in the root of the built website to the build pipeline before I commit and push it to GitHub.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>echo <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;ben.sycha.uk&#39;</span> &gt; <span style="color:#e6db74">${</span>OUTPUT_DIR<span style="color:#e6db74">}</span>/CNAME
</span></span></code></pre></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How to quickly tram a FDM print bed</title><link>https://ben.sycha.uk/til/how-to-quickly-tram-fdm-print-bed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ben.sycha.uk/til/how-to-quickly-tram-fdm-print-bed/</guid><description>Problem I have never been a big fan of the using a piece of paper under the nozzle to tram different spots on the bed and I have always wanted to quickly just know the difference in height at each bed screw. I have a BLTouch installed so there has to be a better way.
First solution I started off by using an OctoPrint macro plugin to move the head to screw positions and then use G30 to probe the distance.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="problem">Problem</h2>
<p>I have never been a big fan of the using a piece of paper under the nozzle to tram different spots on the bed and I have always wanted to quickly just know the difference in height at each bed screw. I have a BLTouch installed so there has to be a better way.</p>
<h2 id="first-solution">First solution</h2>
<p>I started off by using an OctoPrint macro plugin to move the head to screw positions and then use <em>G30</em> to probe the distance. This was helpful but the feedback was spread over many response messages and I would have to work out the offset relevant to a particular screw. Doable but a bit to much hunting for values and maths in my head.</p>
<h2 id="best-solution-so-far">Best solution so far</h2>
<p>Then I found <a href="https://marlinfw.org/docs/gcode/G035.html"><em><strong>G35 Tramming Assistant</strong></em></a> in the marlin firmware.</p>
<p>I recompiled my firmware after updating these definitions:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-cpp" data-lang="cpp"><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#75715e">#define ASSISTED_TRAMMING
</span></span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#75715e"></span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#75715e">#define TRAMMING_POINT_XY { {  31, 31 }, { 271,  31 }, { 271, 271 }, { 31, 271 } }
</span></span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#75715e"></span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#75715e">#define REPORT_TRAMMING_MM 
</span></span></span></code></pre></div><p>Now when I run <em>G35</em> all screw positions are probed and I get a simple readout like:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-plaintext" data-lang="plaintext"><span style="display:flex;"><span>Turn Front-Right CW by 0 turns and 3 minutes (-0.0300mm)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>Turn Back-Right CCW by 0 turns and 6 minutes (0.0525mm)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>Turn Back-Left CW by 0 turns and 6 minutes (-0.0550mm)
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Simple, easy to follow and saves me some brain cycles.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>